Folder inventory to the Michael Burda biographical and Ronald Reagan inaugural materials collection, 1969-2003 MS2300
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Michael Burda biographical and Ronald Reagan inaugural materials collection
1969-2003
1981-1985
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Burda, Michael
MS2300
1 Linear Feet 2 document boxes
These materials in this collection relate to the work of Michael Burda related to both Inaugurations of Ronald Reagan in 1981 and 1985. There is material detailing the distribution of the special whiskey commemorating the inauguration of Ronald Reagan. The presentation of the whiskey was made at a reception in Washington honoring President Reagan and the doctors at George Washington University Medical Center who were responsible for saving the President's life following the shooting in 1981. These materials date from 1969-2003 with the bulk covering 1981-1985.
Arrangement
Arranged in no particular order.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Michael Burda, Circa 2003.
Biographical / Historical
In 1953, Michael Burda founded Burda Associates an insurance consultant/broker company. Two of the organizations Burda Associates represented were the National Association of Letter Carriers and the American Postal Workers Union. In this role, Burda Associates negotiated to establish insurance plans for postal employees. In 1981, Burda hosted a reception in Washington in honor of the GW Hospital doctors who saved President Ronald Reagan's life after an assassination attempt, just as they had saved his own life in previous medical procedures. For the occasion, he distributed a special whiskey to commemorate the 1981 presidential inauguration. In 1999 to commemorate his work with the postal unions and to promote the work of the institution that had treated him, he and his wife Eleanor endowed two scholarships to the GW School of Medicine and Health Sciences. This scholarship foundation assists the sons and daughters of members of the American Postal Workers Union (APWU) and the National Association of Letter Carriers (NALC).
The collection contains a transcript of an oral history interview on Burda's experiences as an intelligence officer during World War II.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, correspondence, newspaper articles, and one videocassette. These materials relate to the work of Michael Burda related to both Inaugurations of Ronald Reagan in 1981 and 1985. There is material detailing the distribution of the special whiskey commemorating the inauguration of Ronald Reagan. The presentation of the whiskey was made at a reception in Washington honoring President Reagan and the doctors at George Washington University Medical Center who were responsible for saving the President's life following the shooting in 1981. These materials date from 1969-2003 with the bulk covering 1981-1985.
Bourbon whiskey; Inaugurations; Presidents Inauguration; Scotch whisky; Burda, Michael
- The Life and Times of Michael Burda, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  This document contains an oral history with Mr. Burda.
- Ronald Reagan Liquor letter, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Michael Burda commemorative bourbon whiskey for Ronald Reagan's inauguration, 1981 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Commemorative cards, Circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from Michael burda about copyright logo, Chasqui, 1981 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from Michael Burda, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photographs, Circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Reagan 1985 Inaugural liqour list (Box 1, Folder 8)
- news articles on whiskey, alcohol and Ronald Reagan, 1969-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photograph, 1981 June 3 (Box 1, Frame 1)
  note on photograph: "Photo taken at Burda Associates' reception honoring President Ronald Reagan and the doctors at George Washington University Medical Center who were responsible for saving his life. Reception held June 3, 1981, at the International Club, Washington, D.C."
  identified people: Michael Burda, Eleanor Spagnolo
- Photograph, 1981 June 3 (Box 1, Frame 2)
  identified people: Michael Burda, Silvio Conte (Rep. Congressman, MA), Lud Andolsek (President NARFE), Robert Michel (Congressman Rep. Minority leader)
- Photograph, 1981 June 3 (Box 1, Frame 3)
  identified people: Michael Burda and Vincent Sombrotto (Presient NALC)
- Scrapbook [1/4], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook [2/4], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook [3/4], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook [4/4], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- VHS, 1981 (Box 2, Videocassette 1)